A Guide to the Miscellaneous Historical Newspapers Collection, 1788-1828
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Special Collections, James Madison University
Miscellaneous Historical Newspapers Collection 1788-1828
Special Collections, James Madison University
SC# NEWS
One newspaper box; x 1.73 linear feet; 1" x 20.75" x 24.50"
The Miscellaneous Historical Newspapers Collection, 1788-1828, consists of one newspaper box (1.73 linear feet), containing twelve newspaper issues from nine Early American newspapers.
Various
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred from the Madison Center at James Madison University to Special Collections in Carrier Library in February 2010 prior to the Center's closing that summer.
Accruals
This collection may receive accruals of other miscelleneous historical newspapers should circumstances so warrant.
Historical Information
The items in this collection were transferred from the James Madison Center for Liberty & Learning, which was founded in 1999 to honor the legacy of the nation's fourth President and Father of the United States Constitution. Prior to its closing in 2010, the Center served as a repository for information on Madison's life and times (1751-1836) as well as that of the Federalist Era. The Center annually offered seminars, workshops, internships and other professional opportunities for K-12 students, teachers, and members of the community. The Center also played a role in a variety of campus special events including Constitution Day, Madison Week, the Centennial celebrations, and the Jamestown 2007 commemorations. On March 4, 2009 as part of the bicentennial commemorations of James Madison's presidency, the Center published Liberty & Learning: The Essential James Madison.
Scope and Content
The Miscellaneous Historical Newspapers Collection, 1788-1828, consists of one newspaper box (1.73 linear feet), containing twelve newspaper issues from nine Early American newspapers.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically, then chronologically.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
See also the John A. Sawhill Collection, 1756-1848, which contains two issues of the London newspaper the Whitehall Evening Post from the years 1756 and 1775, which reflect the prevailing British perspective on world events at the time.
Contents List
- Boston Gazette
  - February 16, 1809 v. 25, no. 48
  - March 26, 1810 v. 42, no. 26
- Columbian Centinal
  - November 20, 1811 no. 2282
  - December 13, 1815 no. 3306
- The Connecticut Courant
  - July 22, 1799 v. 34, no. 1800
- Dunlap's American Daily Advertiser
  - August 5, 1793 no. 4533
- Independent Chronicle
  - July 19, 1813 v. 45, no. 3387
  - September 25, 1815 v. 47, no. 5393
- The Independent Gazetteer, or, The Chronicle of Freedom
  - April 30, 1788 v. 7, no. 743
- National Intelligencer
  - April 16, 1810 v. 10, no. 1465
- New-England Palladium
  - March 26, 1802 v. 19, no. 25
- New York American
  - December 30, 1828 v. 9, no. 827